Hayes Crowley – Full Stack Engineer

hayescrowley@gmail.com � Atlanta, GA

http://hayescrowley.com • https://github.com/Froglegg • https://www.linkedin.com/in/hayes-crowley/

SUMMARY

Experienced full-stack engineer with a background in Digital Marketing and Education, with a firm grasp on the latest tools and technologies for developing and driving a successful digital product. I've developed and built sites for Enterprise-scale companies as well as smaller NGO's as a full-time employee and freelance contractor.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Highly skilled in React.js and MERN (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node) development, JavaScript ES6, MySQL, CSS Grid/Flexbox and Sass, Bootstrap, and RESTful API development. Experienced with several applications including VS Code, iTerm, TFS, Git, Postman and PhotoShop. Familiar with object-oriented programming (OOP) fundamentals, Agile software development, MVC Architecture, Java, PHP, WordPress, Drupal, Contentful, and Sitefinity.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Assurant Sept. 2018 – Present

UI Engineer / Content Manager

Atlanta, GA

• Built out 20 enterprise websites to spec in Agile digital product team; building campaign page UI based on high-res mockups; daily UI (CSS, JS and Bootstrap) tweaks; Node.js API (TrustPilot, Sprinklr) development; GTM, Google Analytics management; Sharepoint site development and CMS technical documentation.

CARE USA Aug. 2016 – Sept. 2018

Web Developer

Atlanta, GA

 Developed several micro-sites in WordPress, tweaked PHP/WP hook plugins and built UI to spec. Managed content in Drupal and Contentful. Liaised with agencies and assisted in developing content strategy.

WHISTLE PIG LLC Aug. 2016 – Present

Web Developer

Atlanta, GA

 Past clients include CARE USA, CARE Switzerland, Center for community Transitions, AfriCare, African Entrepreneur Collective

PROJECTS

View my Github or see my full portfolio @ http://hayescrowley.com/portfolio

StyleFish (React.js / MongoDB / Node.js fashion application), ReactBooks (React.js / MongoDB / Node.js "good reads" application), Guru (Node JS + MySQL employee development application), React I Ching (React.js modular memory game), etc. (see http://hayescrowley.com/portfolio for full list of projects and experiments)

EDUCATION

Georgia Tech Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

Nov. 2019

Full stack, 24-week intensive coding boot camp focusing on React.JS / Node.js / MySQL / MongoDB (MERN) development, as well as an introduction to Java and OOP fundamentals.

Georgia State University

May 2018